[{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following can quote its shares on the stock exchange?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["partnership","co-operative society","sole proprietorship","public limited company"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The authority given to a bank to make regular payment on behalf of a customer is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["credit transfer","bank endorsement","standing order","Bank overdraft"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>When an order cheque is endorsed it becomes a<\/strong><\/p>","options":["confirmed cheque","Bearer cheque","cleared cheque","Dishonoured cheque"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The instruments of credit include&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["bill boards and postal stamps","payment voucher and statement of account","bills of exchange and promissory notes","bills of exchange and salary vouchers"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The most important advantage of privatization is the enhancement of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["accountability","profitability","efficiency","liquidity"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The main requirement for admission to the second-tier securities&nbsp; market is the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["provision of a three year trading record","creating of a good atmosphere for growth and development","guaranteeing of dividends to shareholders","disclosure of all trading activities"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>One major advantages of a credit and thrift cooperative is that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["there  are no legal restrictions","each member has a vote during meetpings","it encourages saving habit","it can approach government for a loan"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The business environment that takes into account the age distribution ethinic mix and educational level of the consumer is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["natural environment","cultiural environment","economic environment","demographic environment"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Citizens are against privatization mainly because of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the likelihood of monopoly","ineffective management","increased prices of the goods and services","the rationalization of organization"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Citizen are against privatization mainly because of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the likelihood of monoploy","ineffective management","increased pricesof the goods and services","the rationalization of oprganization"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The major determinant of Fire insurance premium is the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["owner of the property to be insured","extent of  fire damage anticipated","usefulness of the property to the owner","type and structure of the property to be insured"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following businesses must have at least one member with unlimited liability?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["limited liability company","limited partnership","public enterprise","normal partnership"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>if a country wishes to discourage imports it.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["subidizes export","remove quotes","imposes tarrifs","encourages free trade"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The refund of a duty which had been paid on imported goods that are later reexported is known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["customs drawback","mate's receipt","surtex","export tax"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The international trade, the direct exchange of goods for goods is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["counter trade","multilateral trade","bilateral trade","entrepot trade"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which of the following business units are profits shared on the basis of membership patronage?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["public enterprise","partnership","co-operative society","public limited company"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A business becomes a seperate legal entity after it has&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["started operation","been incorporated","been insured","been accepted by the public"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following makes sales possible without a sales attendant?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["franking machine","telex machine","fax machine","vending machine"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following services is rendered by the central bank?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["provision of brokerage sevices","safe keeping of cash and other valuable","discounting bills for exchange","issuring currency notes"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is the main purpose of a third party insurance?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["indemnify an injured outsider","indemnity the insured","protect the vehicle against theft","compensate the driver for injuries sustained"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following makes an offence for a dealer to give misleading information about goods to consumers?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Restrictive trade practices","Trade description act","consumer protection act","consumer purchase act"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If a company is described as \"listed, it means&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["its shares can be traded on the stock exchange","it is about to be voluntarily liquidated","it is duly registered by the registrar of companies","it has been the blacklisted"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following implies that the price quoted includes the cost of insurance and carriage?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["F.O.B","F.A.S","C.O.D","C.I.F"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following countries is not a member of ECOWAS?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["capr verde","monorovia","mauritania","guinea"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>There are some aspect o the law which give protection and encouragemment to individuals and businesses. Three of these are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["patent, copyright and trade mark","patent, ratification and copyright","trade mark, loyality and patent","patent , trade mark and estopel"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following statement are true except one&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the personnel deparrtment handles all ,maters concerning staff","the accounts department take charge of contacts buildings and insurance matters","the production departments in charge od design and quality control","in the purchases department takes charge of storage and control of stock"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following terms is used for marine insurance when the cargo suffers partial loss?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["General average","particular average","floating policy","open cover"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The use of coin-operated machines to sell goods is a form of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["personal selling","retailing","wholesaliing","mail-order"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following group is paid first, when a firm liquidates?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ordinary","shareholders","debentures","cumulative"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statement is true about sea transport<\/strong><\/p>","options":["all ships have specific routes to ply","all ships must be insured at every journey","all ships are insured from separately from the crew","all ship normally arrive at their destination with goods"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>A sole proprietor insured his goods worth N200,000 for half the value. There was a fire incident in which goods valued N80,000 were destroyed. The value of compensation expected from the indurer is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N40,000","N80,000","N100,000","N200,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>For the establishment of a powerful consumers association in nigeria to exist there must be&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Financial and moral support from the public","honest and committed leadership","allocation of goods from the producers","freedom from external influence"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>If a partnership deed is silent on how profits are to be shared, partner share profits<\/strong><\/p>","options":["in the ratio of the value of business secured by each partner for the partnership","in the ratio or partners' capital contributions","in an equal proportion irrespective of partners  capital contributions","according to duties performed by each other partner"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>If a partnership deed is silent on how profits are to be shared, partner share profits<\/strong><\/p>","options":["in the ratio of the value of business secured by each partner for the partnership","in the ratio or partners' capital contributions","in an equal proportion irrespective of partners  capital contributions","according to duties performed by each other partner"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>If a partnership deed is silent on how profits are to be shared, partner share profits<\/strong><\/p>","options":["in the ratio of the value of business secured by each partner for the partnership","in the ratio or partners' capital contributions","in an equal proportion irrespective of partners  capital contributions","according to duties performed by each other partner"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>If a partnership deed is silent on how profits are to be shared, partner share profits<\/strong><\/p>","options":["in the ratio of the value of business secured by each partner for the partnership","in the ratio or partners' capital contributions","in an equal proportion irrespective of partners  capital contributions","according to duties performed by each other partner"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>one of the implication of the incorperation of a company is that&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["it is more difficulty for the company to raise loans","the company can use but cannot be used","the company's property becomes distinguished from that of its members","its member becomes liable for all the debts of the company"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Right issue means the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["issues of shares to the direction of a company on favourable terms","issues of shares by a company only to the comnpany","right of shareholders to vote on any issue","issues of shares to shareholders on favourable terms"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Motivation is an essential element in management because<\/strong><\/p>","options":["leads to the improvement of staff welfare","encourages individuals to work achieving the organization's objectives","reduces friction among employees in the process of achieving the organization's objectives","helps to eliminate industrial disharmony"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following sets of items were used as a medium of exchange before money was introduced to nigeria&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["cowries, iron rods brass rods and copper wires","iron rods copper rods manila and cowries","cowries manila brass rods and copper wires","copper wires bras wires cowries and iron rods"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a veritable source of funds to a public limited liability company&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a government financial grants","advances and loans from banks","internally generated funds","funds from sale of shares"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a veritable source of funds to a public limited liability company&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a government financial grants","advances and loans from banks","internally generated funds","funds from sale of shares"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which combination of the below are basic requirement as business resources? i. money and machines ii. materials and money iii. market and man iv. materials and man&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["i and ii","ii and iii","i and iv","ii and iv"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>A document which advertises the shares of a company is known as&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["memorandum of satisfaction","dividede warrant","deed","prospectus"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not an advantage of derived from working for a large establishment&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["more fringe establishment","great specialization is possible","at all career ladder","greater job security"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sale of foriegn investment and gold reserve can be used to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["correct a budget deficit","increase invisible imports","correct adverse balance of payments","correct adverse balance of trade"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The difference between the cost of goods sold and the sales value is known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["net profit","net loss","gross profit or loss","surplus"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"}]